Bona Brian Siagian

(+62) 822 1929 8128 • bonabriansiagian@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/bonabrian https://bonabrian.com • https://github.com/bonabrian

SUMMARY

Full-stack engineer with 4+ years of experience using a range of Frontend and Backend technologies like Java/Kotlin (Spring), PHP (Laravel), Javascript/Typescript (Vue, React).

Developed scalable software with specifications and business requirements. Perform technical analysis and testing to deliver business value through quality software.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Engineer at Investree

November 2020 - Present

- Mainly working in Kotlin (Spring) for Back-end and PHP (Laravel) for Legacy and Javascript (Vue) for Front-end.
- Work with Product Managers, QA, and other developer team members to plan new features or tech
 enhancements.
- Built configurable loan automation process to improve business operations using RabbitMQ that eliminates 132 clicks per loan process, eliminating 49 manual data input.
- Perform unit tests for every new feature and enhancement at least 80% coverage both back-end and front-end.
- Centralized structured logging to provide monitoring, auditability, business metrics and service metrics (Elastic Search, New Relic).
- Continuous integration and delivery with Jenkins and Git.
- Move storage into proper and more secure.
- Help establish technical standards, best practices, and design patterns.
- Responsible for performing code reviews.
- Deliver delightful UX and performant front-end software.
- Build reusable UI components.
- Followed agile methodology for application development process.
- Integrated with 3rd party services for digital signature, generating documents, and payment system.

Full Stack Engineer at Varnion

June 2018 - August 2020

- Maintain & update old codebases to the latest framework and establish design patterns.
- Define and restructure the database schema to minimize data redundancy and enhance performance.
- Improved a Telegram bot using PHP (Slim) for network monitoring.
- Implemented elastic search for network monitoring that increases 30% load time and rendered data visually in real time and using Redis for caching.
- Created a company's profile and careers page using Javascript (Vue and React) for Front-end and PHP (Laravel) for API and CMS.
- Identify and design new features for the company's products.
- Coded an internal application for data management using PHP (Laravel).

EDUCATION

Universitas Komputer Indonesia, Bandung

September 2013 - April 2018

Bachelor's of Information Technology GPA: 3.11/4.0

SKILLS

- Java, Kotlin, PHP, Javascript, Typescript
- Spring, Laravel, Vue, React, Node.js, JSON, JQuery
- HTML5, CSS, SASS, Tailwind, Bootstrap
- Redis, RabbitMQ, Elastic Search
- Git, Jenkins, Jira, Unit Testing
- Databases, SQL, MySQL, NoSQL
- Agile, Scrum, Continuous Delivery

PROJECTS

Transaxi (Personal Project)

Transaxi is multi vendor marketplace that I created to improve my full stack development skill and I work as full stack engineer

- Architected system and database structure
- Implemented Midtrans Payment Gateway, Rajaongkir, Google Maps API
- Wrote using Laravel for backend (My plan to migrate using Golang) and Vue.js for frontend
- Using RabbitMQ for queue system and Redis for caching

Yummy Bros (https://yummybros.com), Singapore

Yummy Bros is an on-demand healthy food delivery service and provides Asian dishes that are healthier, nutritionally transparent, affordable, and tasty.

Working as frontend developer

- Coded Storefront using Next.js, applied SSR (Server-Side Rendering)
- Built Back Office (CMS) using React.js
- Using Bootstrap as styling CSS framework

Wikas (https://wikas.id)

Wikas is News Portal like kumparan.com

I develop this application using Laravel, Vue.js, and Bootstrap

Nazar (https://nazar.id)

Nazar is a multi vendor ecommerce store.

I work as Android developer

- Developed using Kotlin
- Using Retrofit to communicate with API
- Integrated with 3rd party services like Google Maps, Espay, Rajaongkir

More projects can be found on

bonabrian.com/projects

LANGUAGES

- Bahasa Indonesia
- English